# Muhammad Ahmed

Phouse no 72 Askari 3 DHA Multan 🔀 ma774636@gmail.com 📞 03049522067

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-ahmed-25992a17b/

fwerr. muhammadahme661

# PROFILE

Experienced and dedicated Data Analyst with several years of experience identifying efficiencies and problem areas within data streams while communicating project needs. Capable of receiving and monitoring data from a variety of data sources, including Power BI, SQL, and Excel. Ability to synthesize quantitative information and interact effectively with colleagues and clients. Proven track record of generating summary documents for senior management for monthly and quarterly audit and compliance reporting.

	•	SKILLS	
Customer Service and Support		<b>SEO Techniques</b> on-page SEO	
SQL		<b>Problem Solver</b>	
Microsoft Excel		Time Managment	
Analytical Skills Team Work Data Visalization Data analysis		Multitasking Ability	
		Communication	
		Python	
		Programming Skills HTML,CSS,Javascrip	ot,BootStrap

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

10/2022 – present Multan, Pakistan

### **Junior Software Developer Defense Housing Authority**

- Participating in daily scrum meetings, sprint planning, unit testing, and bug fixes.
- Developing and maintaining a reporting system for support users, managers, and executives to keep track of support calls both on a moment-to-moment basis and over time using PHP, MySQL, HTML, Bootstrap, and CSS.

 Assisting the Senior Developer with the design, development, deployment, and maintenance of all menu maintenance portal code using PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, and Javascript.

### 06/2022 – present Multan, Pakistan

# Oracle SQL Developer Intern Sunrays Textile Mills Limited

- Created reports and forms for different database tables in Apex Oracle.
- Formulated SQL queries, functions and processes as per customization requirement.
- Review and provide a recommendation for design optimization.
- Worked on front-end designing and back-end PL/SQL scripts.

# 03/2020 - 11/2021

# **Shopify Store Manager**

#### **Fiverr**

- Managed more than 5 Shopify online stores.
- Maintain and make regular updates to Shopify store, including SEO tags, product updates, page listings, and inventory management.
- Increased customer growth and sales through various approaches of store by 60%.
- Tracked and analyzed web analytics to recommend proactive adjustments to strategies.
- Contributed to mock-ups, email campaigns and social media content.

#### 01/2021 - 04/2021

# **SEO Manager**

#### **Fiverr**

- Recommended changes to website architecture, content and linking to improve SEO positions for target keywords.
- Created dynamic SEO strategies to exceed market
- competitors and meet client needs.
- Analyzed and audited clients' websites to address performance issues.
- Used different tools like Google page insights,GTX metrix ,SEMrush,Ahrefs,Google Keyword Planner,Google search console and Google
- analytics

# 04/2020 – 07/2020 Guangdong, China

# Virtual Assistant TYD Electronics

- Have done products product listings and store management of their online store on Alibaba site.
- Performed email marketing manually through used of customer LinkedIn profiles.

#### Multan, Pakistan

# Network Administrator Internee DHA Multan

• LAN, WAN, internet, and other wireless, local area network, and other data communications systems and segments design, implementation, and testing.

- Worked closely with the managers of each department to make system upgrades go more smoothly.
- Diagnosed and solved problems of other departments' networking issues
- Performing network hardware and software troubleshooting, performance tuning, and security auditing.

# **EDUCATION**

2017 - 2021Sargodha, Pakistan

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** The University Of Lahore

- I have done various projects on Artificial intelligence and computer vision like flower detection and vehicle classification and counting.
- My FYP project was Crop Disease Detection where we used computer vision technology to identify which type a disease a particular crop is infected.
- We achieved a very authentic result and our accuracy in disease detection was 80%.

2015 – 2017 Sargodha, Pakistan

**Intermediate of Computer Science Army Public School And College** 

2012 - 2014Jhelum, Pakistan

**Army Public School And College** 



# **CERTIFICATES**

• Prepare, Clean, Transform, and Load Data using Power BI From Coursera 🗷  Intermediate SQL Queries By DataCamp Ø



Urdu **English** 

Matric